# MOHAMED ELSAYED ADBELWADOOD OMARA

# Front End Developer / React Js

## **CONTACT**

- 0 106 8465 753
- Mohamedomara674@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/mohamedomara0/

Military status

### **Exempted**

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Java Script, ES6, JSX, TS and AJAX
- React-IS
- Redux, Redux-Toolkit and Hooks
- Restful APIs
- HTML, HTML5
- CSS, CSS3 and SASS
- (Bootstrap 3, 4 and 5),( reactstrap, ant-design and Material-UI)
- JQuery
- SEO
- Git, Github and Gitlab
- MVC Angular JS
- PHP
- C++ , Java 2SE and Java Swing
- MySQL Database and SQL
- ERP NEXT
- Linux Ubuntu
- Keycloak and SSO integration

### SW DEVELOPMENT METHODOLOGIES

- Agile
- Restful API
- MVC OOP UML Design

## SW DEVELOPMENT TOOLS

- Github
- Jira
- Gitlab

# **PROFILE**

An ambitious Software Engineer Specialized in the field of web development and design to participate in escalating organization superiority by investing utilized cumulative knowledge and up to date practical skills, I'm very passion about technology and computer sciences. I have a strong background in Front-End Web Development, React-Js and restful APIs .Also, have an intermediate background in the Back-End field.

## **EDUCATION**

Zagazig University, Faculty of Computers and Informatics, 2015 – 2019 computer science department

Bachelor's degree of Computer Science & Software Engineering. (Very good)

#### **Graduation Project**

My graduation project is a test bank questions for doctors in Zagazig University (Excellent)

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Front-End Developer at Variiance

5 /12 /2020 - Present

- Worked with team on 5 main projects (VLC (<u>Live</u>) VOL (<u>Live</u>) VTS (<u>Live</u>) Payment portal (<u>Live</u>) Variiance website (<u>Live</u>).
- Converting UX to fully developed UI.
- Responsible for high quality of user interface design deliverables including integrating with the APIs from backend side, site maps, wireframes and prototypes.
- Developing the Multi languages of the website.
- Develop in a large-scale projects.
- Carrying out quality tests to discover errors and optimize usability..
- Optimizes application for Search engine (SEO).

### Front-End web - development at IRC Company

1 /7 /2020 - 1/12/2020

- Converting UX to fully developed UI.
- Responsible for high quality of user interface design deliverables including integrating with the APIs from backend side, site maps, wireframes and prototypes.
- Optimizes application for Search engine (SEO).

## Work as freelancer as front-end web-development

1 /2 /2019 - Present

# **PROJECTS**

- Alsharhan ecommerce watches and accessories (React Js Redux Css JSX ) <u>Live</u>
- Mahawer Dashboard for vendors and admin ecommerce (React Js Redux Css JSX JWT – Axios – authentication – ant-design) <u>Live</u>
- Work on Mahawer Website ecommerce for users (React Js Redux Css JSX JWT Axios – authentication – ant-design)
- Landing page for doctor clinic (React Js Redux Css JSX Axios Reactstrap) Live
- Landing page for Constructions (React Js Redux Css JSX Axios Reactstrap) <u>Live</u>
- Landing page for investment (React Js Redux Css JSX Axios Reactstrap) Live
- Portfolio example for front-end with react Js (Html- Css- JavaScript JSX –React Js )
- Complaints Website for university student (Html Css- JavaScript php My sql- Ajax)
- Volunteer for the people of Jeddah ( Html Css- JavaScript php My sql- Ajax) Source
- Bright mind Website for the primary student ( Html Css- JavaScript php My sql Ajax)
- Rescue car for leased cars to Tenants ( Html Css- JavaScript php My sql Ajax)
- Online uniform shopping system ( Html Css- JavaScript php My sql Ajax) Source
- Desktop app for elarzaq shop for cashier (java SE- java swing- MySQL)

LANGUAGE INTERESTS SOFT SKILLS GITHUB